metastock.com 2016-11-26

# Privacy Statement

This Privacy Statement relates solely to the online information collection and use practices of our Web Sites located at [www.metastock.com](http://www.metastock.com/), www.qchartsmetastockpro.com, [http://forum.equis.com](http://forum.equis.com/), [http://forum.metastock.com](http://forum.metastock.com/), [www.echarts.com](http://www.echarts.com/), [www.equis.com ](http://www.echarts.com/)and [www.reutersdatalink.com](http://www.echarts.com/) (these “Web Sites”), and not to any subdomains of these Web Sites. We recognize that many visitors and users of these Web Sites are concerned about the information they provide to us, and how we treat that information. This Privacy Statement, which may be updated from time to time, has been developed to address those concerns.

Your use of this Web Site indicates to us that you have read and accept our privacy practices, as outlined in this Privacy Statement. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Statement, please contact:[sales@MetaStock.com](mailto:sales@metastock.com)

#### What Information Do We Collect?

When you visit this Web Site, you may provide us with two types of information (1) personally identifiable information that you knowingly choose to disclose, which is collected on an individual basis, and (2) general user information that does not contain personally identifiable information, which is collected on an aggregate basis as you browse the Web Site. In some cases, if you choose not to provide us with requested information, you may not be able to access all of this Web Site’s content or services. 

#### Personal Information We Collect About You

We may collect the following personal information about you:

Personally identifiable information that you knowingly choose to disclose, which is collected on an individual basis 

General user information that does not contain personally identifiable information, which is collected on an aggregate basis as you browse the Web Site. In some cases, if you choose not to provide us with requested information, you may not be able to access all of this Web Site’s content or services. 

MetaStock relationship data:This is data we obtain from our interactions with you, and may include details of the calls you have made to our sales or help desk, visits made to you by our staff, MetaStock (MetaStock) marketing materials you have received, your email communication with our staff, data about your preferred activities for marketing events or the MetaStock events you have attended. Calls made to MetaStock may be monitored and recorded for training and review processes. 

Credit card data:If you are subscribing to our products as an individual, we collect your credit card information in order to maintain your services. 

Product usage data:This is data we obtain about your usage of MetaStock products and may include when and which products you have used and the content and functionality you have used in those products. 

Subscription data:This is data we obtain from our interactions with you and may include the products or data sets to which you subscribe or which you are enabled to access. 

Surveys, competitions, prize draws:This is data you may provide when you participate in our competitions, prize draws or surveys. 

Cookies:Cookies are bits of software that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain MetaStock financial and media products. We use cookies to help us identify product features in which you may have the greatest interest. Cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are using a particular product. Most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies. Please note, however, that without cookies you may not be able to take full advantage of all the product features. 

IP Address:An IP address is a unique identifier that certain electronic devices use to identify and communicate with each other on the Internet. When you use our professional financial and media products, we may view the IP address of the device you use to connect to those products. We use this information to determine the location of the device and to determine the number of devices simultaneously accessing the product.

#### Personally Identifiable Information You Choose to Provide

We may ask for certain personal information from you which is necessary to provide you with the content and/or services you request. For example some of the services which ask you to provide personal information include:

  * Newsletters and subscriptions 
  * Contributing to blogs or to the forum website 
  * Sharing pictures and videos 
  * Submitting questions or feedback 
  * Webinars, free books 
  * Purchase of MetaStock products

#### How Do We Use the Information We Collect?

Information about how we use your personal information is provided on our web-pages at the point you submit your personal information to us. Further We may use the personal information you provide us for the purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations with you or your employer. Specifically, we may use your personal information as follows:

  *  **Administration:** We may use the personal information we collect about you to provide our products and services to you and to assist you in your use of our products. This may include setting up your access to a product, providing assistance or training for your use of the product, alerting you to product changes or maintenance periods and invoicing you or your employer for your use of the product. 

We may also use the personal information you provide us for the purposes of pursuing MetaStock legitimate business interests. Specifically, we may use your personal information as follows

  *  **Product/Service development, testing and improvement** :We may use the personal information we collect about you to develop, test and improve our products. Where we use your personal information in this way we have a policy of anonymizing the information where possible. We may also ask you to participate in surveys to improve our products and service delivery to you. Our surveys allow for customers to remain anonymous. Personal information obtained in our surveys may also be combined in an aggregate form. We use the data obtained through our surveys to plan and implement developments of, and enhancements to, our products, product ranges and areas of customer service. 
  * **Marketing** :We may use certain information you provide to offer you products and services that we believe may be of interest to you or for market research purposes. If you don't wish to receive such offers or to be contacted directly, you may opt out (unsubscribe) as described below.
  * We may provide access to your personally identifiable information when legally required to do so, to co-operate with police investigations or other legal proceedings, to protect against misuse or unauthorized use of these Web Sites, to limit our legal liability and protect our rights, or to protect the rights and safety of visitors to this Web Site or the public. In those instances, the information is provided only for those limited purposes . 

#### How Do You Access and/or Modify Your Personal Information?

If you visit this Web Site and volunteer personally identifiable information, you may modify, update or delete such information at any time by contacting [sales@metastock.com](mailto:sales@metastock.com). You will have the opportunity to access and revise certain personally identifiable information. You should be aware, however, that it is not always possible to completely remove or modify information in our databases. 

#### How Do You Change your Preferences or Unsubscribe from Receiving Information or Marketing?

If you would like to change your preferences or unsubscribe from receiving any of the information that you have requested from us, including marketing material, you may do this by contacting [sales@metastock.com](mailto:sales@metastock.com).

#### Data Security

We take reasonable steps to maintain the security of the personally identifiable information that we collect, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers, as well as installing electronic security systems that guard against unauthorized access. However, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. Accordingly, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information that you transmit to us, so you do so at your own risk.

#### Consent to Share Information

When you provide information to MetaStock we do not sell or share this information with third parties without your express consent. The only exception to this is defined in the Thomson Reuters, Exchanges, and Third Party Add-ons section(s) of the privacy policy. Third parties may from time to time offer deals or training on products that require that we share information, however, we will not share this information unless you give your express consent through an opt in process. Once you have shared your information with a third party, we cannot be held responsible for their privacy policies. 

#### Consent to Transfer

Please be aware that as MetaStock is a global company, we may transfer your personal information to countries that may not guarantee the same level of protection for personal information as the one in which you reside. We are taking appropriate steps to provide an adequate level of protection to your personal information and no matter where you live, your personal information will be processed in accordance with the other provisions of this Privacy Statement. By using our Web Site, participating in any of our services and/or providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.

#### Thomson Reuters

MetaStock uses Thomson Reuters permissioning and authentication systems to allow you access to MetaStock, MetaStock Pro, and MetaStock XENITH. By subscribing to or for any of these services your information will be automatically shared with Thomson Reuters to allow you access to the products you have purchased. By sharing information with Thomson Reuters you agree to their privacy policies:http://thomsonreuters.com/privacy_policy/ and other software policies that they may have. 

#### Exchanges

Exchanges reserve the right to contact any subscribers to their exchanges for any reason. When you subscribe to a real-time exchange (such as the New York Stock Exchange, or the London Metals Exchange), MetaStock is required to pass your contact information to that exchange. Typically client exchange communication will come from MetaStock but each exchange you have subscribed to reserves the right to contact you directly.

#### Third Party Add-ons

Select MetaStock add-ons use third party systems to authenticate and authorize usage to allow you access to products. In order for you to be able to access an add-on that uses these third party systems, MetaStock must share your information with a third party. MetaStock strives to have confidentiality agreements with these vendors to ensure that your information is not misused or shared, however, we cannot guarantee the usage of third party systems through systems and services that we do not maintain. If you have questions on which of the add-ons use these third party systems please contact MetaStock sales. By using any of these products, you agree to have your information shared with a third party. 

#### Links

These Web Sites contain links to third party sites as well as to other sites owned and/or operated by MetaStock. Please be aware that MetaStock is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third party sites. Please also be aware that the privacy policies of other MetaStock sites may differ significantly from the privacy policy of these Web Sites. Therefore, we encourage our users to read the privacy statement of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy Statement applies solely to information collected by this Web Site. 

#### Contacting the Web Site

If you have any questions regarding this privacy statement, the practices of the sites, or your dealings with the Web sites, you can contact:

MetaStock  
4548 South Atherton Drive  
Suite 200  
Salt Lake City, UT 84123

© MetaStock 2016
